<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Facebook on Rukshan&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/facebook/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Facebook on Rukshan&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.140.2</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>2025</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 10:41:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/facebook/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The rings of share - the unsolved problem of sharing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-rings-of-share/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 10:41:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-rings-of-share/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently (last Saturday), I went to the Colombo Street Food Festival. It was a bit crowded for my liking but had awesome music and good beer. I snapped some photos of the event, recorded some clips of the music, and snapped some more photos with the others who I went to the festival with.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Journey In Deleting Facebook and Instagram Accounts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/my-journey-in-deleting-facebook-and-instagram-accounts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 12:10:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/my-journey-in-deleting-facebook-and-instagram-accounts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In April I made a decision that I wanted to make for a very long time. Delete my Facebook and Instagram accounts. I wanted to delete my Facebook and IG accounts for a while. I have even applied to delete my account several times in the past, only to reactivate it within few days. However, this time it was different. I was committed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recycle Bin by Facebook</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recycle-bin-by-facebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 12:19:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recycle-bin-by-facebook/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Facebook likes to collect as much data as possible, and they will try to retain your data as long as possible. This is why you can’t delete your Facebook or Instagram account for one month. They are slowly opening up WhatsApp so the data you communicate with businesses are available for Facebook. Because at the end of the day the data on what you communicate, how you interact with a business, and what businesses you are interested in communicating is more valuable than what you communicate with your friends,&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facebook is combining Messenger and Instagram messaging</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/facebook-is-combining-messenger-and-instagram-messaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 10:05:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/facebook-is-combining-messenger-and-instagram-messaging/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I received this popup notifying me that soon people using Instagram will be able to find and message me on Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Google needs to build an open chat client like Element</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/why-google-needs-to-build-an-open-chat-client-like-element/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 10:53:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/why-google-needs-to-build-an-open-chat-client-like-element/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/element_hq/status/1355290296947499013&#34;&gt;Google recently blocked the Matrix based chat app Element from the Play Store sighting sexual content on the platform.&lt;/a&gt; It’s really hard to define the explanation because WhatsApp, Telegram users of other chat clients also share the same content. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.redpoints.com/blog/telegram-book-piracy/&#34;&gt;Telegram is also known to host groups sharing pirated content as well.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The value of targeted advertising</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-value-of-targeted-advertising/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 16:48:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-value-of-targeted-advertising/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This post will might be the post that will roast me the most. But before triggering your fingers just by reading the title I would like everyone to read my post, and read my argument before jumping in to conclusions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who is sending these mysterious 2FA codes?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/who-is-sending-these-mysterious-2fa-codes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 11:38:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/who-is-sending-these-mysterious-2fa-codes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I read a recent post titled &lt;a href=&#34;https://shkspr.mobi/blog/2021/01/thats-not-how-2fa-works/&#34;&gt;“That’s not how 2FA works”,&lt;/a&gt; it was an interesting read.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I sent this email asking my friends to switch to Signal</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/i-sent-this-email-asking-my-friends-to-switch-to-signal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 09:26:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/i-sent-this-email-asking-my-friends-to-switch-to-signal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know you like to use WhatsApp, I use WhatsApp as well. One of the most important things in WhatsApp that differentiates itself from other messaging apps like Viber, Messenger and Telegram is WhatsApp’s privacy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Signal, thank you for not collecting my data. But I won’t use you.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/signal-thank-you-for-not-collecting-my-data-but-i-wont-use-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 14:24:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/signal-thank-you-for-not-collecting-my-data-but-i-wont-use-you/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Facebook has given an ultimatum for WhatsApp users to either share their data with Facebook or leave the service. And that date is February 8th.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
